

SUMMARY

PhD student in Nanoelectronics at Université de Bordeaux, focusing on high-frequency characterization and semiconductor physics. Experienced in embedded systems and software engineering, with strong skills in C++ and simulation tools, and fluent in English, Hindi and Malayalam.

CONTACT

TÉLÉPHONE: +33 605 750 837

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jojo-varghese-260315146/

E-MAIL

jojov8276@gmail.com

SKILLS

Analytical Thinking Team Player Technical Support MS Office Ansys HFSS K-Layout Electromagnetic Theory Research MS Office

HOBBIES

Cooking Vlogging Badminton

JOJO VARGHESE

Doctoral Student

EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Engineer | Eloit Innovations Pvt Ltd.

Ernakulam, India | Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

- Provided technical support to customers over the phone and via email.
- · Resolving technical issues using SQL query.
- Assisted customers with mobile device configuration.

Software Developer Trainee | Soften Technologies

Ernakulam, India | Aug 2021 - Jul 2022

Assisted in full-stack web development projects using the Django framework.

Research and Development Software Developer | IMG Electronics &Power Systems GmbH

Nordhausen, Germany | Mar 2019 - Jul 2021

- Developed windows desktop application using Microsoft Foundation classes
- · Assisted in firmware development of embedded applications.
- Revisioning of software projects according to the client requirements.
- Code debugging, testing and documentation

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

PhD. | Nanoelectronics

Université de Bordeaux Bordeaux, France | Nov 2023 – till date

Master of Science | Microelectronics

Ernst Abbe Hochschule Jena Jena, Germany | Mar 2019

Bachelor of Technology | Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Cochin University of Science and Technology

Cochin, India | May 2015

LANGUAGES

- Malayalam First Language
- English C1
- Hindi B2
- German B1
- French A1